Ammar El refay Kandel

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

merom8703@gmail.com| Github | LinkedIn | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Software Developer with a passion for coding and creating responsive web applications. I have experience working with remote developers, proficiencies in HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, and React/Redux, and able to adapt to new technologies quickly and efficiently.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Freelance - Full Stack Web Developer

Feb, 2020 - Present

Order-From-Restaurants — This static website simulates ordering food from different restaurants in Egypt. This website has home, search, and details pages.

• Built with: (Html - Css)

Tic-Tac-Toe-Game — This is a game that makes users/players have a fun time.

• Built with: (Ruby - RSpec)

Ruby-Linter — This custom linter deals with the idea of checking ruby script and looking for syntax. It checks some of the unexpected actions in the code.

• Built with: (Ruby - RSpec)

Mentor (Volunteer)

ExpensesRegulator — The purpose of the expenses regulator is to manage users to count their expenses and organize groups of expenses.

• Built with: (Ruby - RSpec - Ruby on Rails - Html - Sass/scss)

Star-Wars-Game — In this project, I build a shooter game using JavaScript's framework phaser3. It is an open-source framework for Canvas and WebGL powered browser games. This game has 4 scenes: gameOver, leaderBoard, main and mainMenu.

Built with: (Javascript - Webpack - Phaser3 - Jest)

HappyMeal - Build a restaurant menu for clients to see different food categories, filter them and see details for every meal.

• Built with: (React.js - Css - @redux-toolkit - Jest)

MICROVERSE

Remote Jan, 2020 – Present

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE Dec, 2020 - Present

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.